Benjamin Vaughan Papers 1746-1900 Mss.B.V46p
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Manuscripts, ca.1780-1812; 0.75 linear feet (Box 28-30)
  Manuscript essays and notes on a startling array of topics written by Benjamin Vaughan, arranged alphabetically by title. Topics range from dueling to dysentery, and like his correspondence, touch on nearly every facet of Vaughan's intellectual interests including science (Concerning geology, granite, phlogiston, meteorology), religion (Locke on religion), agriculture (cultivation of hemp, the olive; horses and improving the breed, the making of hay), Maine (Description of Hallowell, hints for settling the interior), international politics (neutrality, Napoleon), and American politics and society (Louisiana purchase, Negroes).
  Materials relating to politics, medicine, and religion are also located in Series IV.
  - AMs, An Account of some late Proceedings in Congress respecting the project for establishing a First Meridian at Washington; with Remarks, [ca. 1810]; 139 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, An Account of swallows and Swifts, collected from Wilson's Ornithology and Foster's Observations on the Brumal Retreat of the Swallow, 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, An Account of a Voyage undertaken by authority of the King of Spain for Spreading Inoculation by the Kine-pox, 26 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMstcy, Additional Remarks on the Treaty of Commerce with France in 1787, n.d.; 9 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Agreement to open a road between the Connecticut and Kennebec rivers, 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Agriculture, Miscellaneous notes on stockbreeding, farming, etc, n.d.; 53 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Agriculture, Miscellaneous notes on seeds, fruit trees, etc, n.d.; 33 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Agriculture, n.d.; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, An Analysis of Mr. Adair Crawford's book; intended to prove that Animal Heat and Inflammation depend on one common principle, [ca. 1780]; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Architecture, n.d.; 17 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Astronomy, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Astronomy, n.d.; 18 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Aurora Borealis, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Barley, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Berlin Decree, [ca. 1807]; 47 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Book of Jonah, n.d.; 46 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Books, n.d.; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Botanical notes, n.d.; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Bridges, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Bridges, sketch, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Cholera, n.d.; 42 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Churches in London, 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Climate and argiculture, 15 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Compass, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Composition Society, minutes, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Considerations respecting the place in the Northern part of the United States, best suited at this moment for the establishment of a Public Onservatory, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Contents of Sir Isaac Newton's letters to Dr. Bentley, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Coombe, Thomas, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Consumption in New England, 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Cultivation of Olives, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Dueling, n.d.; 13 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Dueling, n.d.; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Earthquakes in Chile, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Egyptian Hieroglyphics, n.d.; 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, International relations, [ca. 1812]; 24 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, A Fragment; containing a series of facts relative to the inflammation of candles, given in the way of analysis, 1779; 26 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Franklin's remarks in Poor Richard, n.d.; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Fruit culture, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, General Advertisement, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Geology, n.d.; 9 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Granite, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Great Lakes Region, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Hallowell, Maine, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Hay, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Hemp, n.d.; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Hermaphroditism in cattle, n.d.; 47 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Hints drawn up for the use of a gentleman on the point of making a tour through the West India Islands, 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Horses, n.d.; 32 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Hume's writing, n.d.; 27 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Illnesses; prescriptions and symptoms, 29 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Innoculation, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Instructions for locating and building a spring house and ice-house, 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Loose Remarks concerning a Board of Trade in Great Britain, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Louisiana purchase and its boundaries, [ca. 1805]; 130 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Maine, n.d.; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Medical notes concerning female complaints, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Memorandum, 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Memorandum of an agreement between Mess. Prescot and Hinkley on theone side and Benjamin Vaughan on the other respecting the frame of a vessel of one hundred and forty tons, 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Meteorological notes, n.d.; 18 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Mineralogy, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Minutes of certain particulars as to comets found in Vince's Complete System of Astronomy, and in La Lande's Astronomy; given in the order in which they stand in these authors, 17 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Mode of cultivating hemp said to be employed in the northern parts of the continent of Europe, n.d.; 18 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Mr. Morgan, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Mumps, n.d.; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Napoleon, n.d.; 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Negotiations for peace, n.d.; 45 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Negroes, n.d.; 5 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Neutrality and the impressment of seamen in U.S and Great Britain relations, 35 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Old age, n.d.; 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Orders in Council of 1807, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, A paper by Mr. Vaughan on the favorable temper of the people of England for the war, 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Petition to the General Court of Massachusetts concerning a bridge, n.d.; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Prescription for Dr. Heberden, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Prize oxen, n.d.; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Phlogiston, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Phlogiston, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Private Hints, n.d.; 11 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Proprietors of estates in the island of St. Christophers, 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Punctuation, n.d.; 48 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Reasons against additional mills, n.d.; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Reasons against a War with Great Britain and against an Alliance with Bonapart, 64 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Reasons in favor of placing the Seat of Government of Maine at the head of the tide-waters of the Kennebec, 12 November 1822; 17 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Receipt for Lord Stanhope's Mortar and Mortar wash, 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Recipes given by Count Rumford, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Remarks on Dr. Priestley's notes upon the manuscript on electricity., 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Remarks on the establishment of a road between Quebec and the head of the tide-water navigation of the Kennebec river, 19 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Rules for comparing the thermometers of Fahrenheit and Reaumur, 6 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Rush Benjamin, n.d.; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Ships, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Short Essay on Duelling; Occasioned by certain remarks made on the murder of Mr. Paul Chadwick, at Malta, on the Kennebec, in September, 1809, 15 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Silk manufacture, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Sketch of instruments endorsed; Dr. Priestley Experiments on Air, 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Stones fallen from the atmosphere; with the relation which they bear to certain other stones and to certain meteors, 62 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Table of simple and compound salts, 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Tavern, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Taxation, n.d.; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Thermometrical observations, n.d.; 11 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Thermometrical observations, n.d.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    see oversize box.
  - AMs, Time-keeping, n.d.; 15 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Trade with Tibet, n.d.; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Treatment of Dysentery, n.d.; 12 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Trees, n.d.; 11 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Un Corse la finira, n.d.; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Un Coup d'oeil; translation of Rural Socrates, 1800; 37 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Vaughan, Charles, [ca. 1806]; 74 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    removed for conservation.
  - AMs, Vaughan, Samuel, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Vaughan, Sarah Manning, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Vaughan Family, n.d.; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Water, n.d.; 11 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, West Indies, 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Wharves, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
- Series IV. Subject Files, 2.75 linear feet (Box 31-41)
  Rough notes on miscellaneous subject, arranged roughly into 16 subseries:
  - Politics, n.d.; No. 1; 0.25 linear feet
    - AMs, Miscellaneous papers concerning political subjects, n.d.; 0.25 linear feet; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Medicine, n.d.; No. 2; 0.25 linear feet
    - AMs, Miscellaneous papers concerning medical subjects, n.d.; 0.25 linear feet; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Religion, n.d.; No. 3; 0.25 linear feet
    - AMs, Miscellaneous papers concerning religion, n.d.; 0.25 linear feet; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Business and finance, No. 4
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Charles, 1759-1839
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Charles, 1759-1839
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Samuel, 1762-1827
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Samuel, Sr., 1720-1802
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, Samuel, Sr., 1720-1802
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, William Oliver, 1783-1826
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, William Oliver, 1783-1826
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, William Oliver, 1783-1826
    - AD, Bills, receipts, etc, Vaughan, William Oliver, 1783-1826
    - AD, Vaughan Family, Miscellaneous bills, receipts, etc
    - AD, Vaughan Family, Miscellaneous bills, receipts, etc
    - AD, Vaughan Family, Miscellaneous bills, receipts, etc
    - AD, Vaughan Family, Miscellaneous bills, receipts, etc
    - AD, Vaughan Family, Miscellaneous bills, receipts, etc
  - Miscellaneous, No. 5; 0.25 linear feet
    - AMs, Miscellaneous papers, pertaining probably to the book he never wrote, 0.25 linear feet; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Mathematical notes, n.d.; No. 6
    - AMs, Miscellaneous mathematical notes, n.d.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Scientific notes, n.d.; No. 7
    - AMs, Miscellaneous scientific notes, n.d.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - AMs, Weather notes, n.d.; No. 8
    - AMs, Weather observations, n.d.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Miscellaneous, No. 9
    - AMs, Miscellaneous papers, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Negative and positive electricity., No. 10; 3 p.
    - AMs, Discharging Distance (Concerning negative and positive electricity.), 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Hume's argument against the existence of causes, 1780 March 28; No. 11
    - AMs, Hume's argument against the existence of causes, 1780 March 28; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - The effect of liberty on genius, n.d.; No. 12; 10 p.
    - AMs, The effect of liberty on genius, n.d.; 10 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Lectures, n.d.; No. 13
    - AMs, Lectures, n.d.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
  - Various subjects (when paging check Ser. III, too), n.d.; No. 14
    - AMs, Animal magnetism, 1784 August 11; 3 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - ALS to [?], 1818 November 20; 1 p.; Pettibone, Daniel
    - ALS to Miss Vaughans, 1811 November 20; 4 p.; Vaughan, William Oliver, 1783-1826
    - ALS to [Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854], n.d.; 1 p.; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    - Omnibus Christi Fidelibus....., 1797 April 10; 1 p.
    - Omnibus Christi Fidelibus....., 1798 February 9; 1 p.
    - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 1810 July 27; 4 p.; M. B
    - [Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835], 1805 August 3; 4 p.; Pinckney, Eliz
    - AMstcy, Travels in New England, 1812; 5 p.; Dwight, Timothy, 1752-1817
    - AMs, poem, n.d.; 1 p.
    - Extracts of letters to Emma Gardiner, 1812-1816; 4 p.
    - AMs, Specific gravities of Metals & Semi-metals according to several authors, n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Person's horizontal top described as to its effect, but not its structure by James Short, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Rules proposed with regard to the floating capital of the house, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Russia, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Punctuation and other similar aids to the reader of literary composition, 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, China, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Decree of the National Convention of France, dated May 9, 1793; (second year of the French Revolution), 7 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, General Armstong's letter to M. Champagny, minister of foreign relations, n.d.; 4 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Petty Vaughan, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, The running at large of rams at certain seasons, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Time, chronometors, etc, n.d.; 8 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - AMs, Cui Bono, n.d.; 2 p.; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - Map, Vaughan Family property line, n.d.; 1 p.
    - Vaughan Family, miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - Miscellaneous, Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    - ALS to Merrick, John, 1766-1861, 1820 May 12; 2 p.; Page, Rufus
    - ALS to Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835, 3 p.; 1804 February 22; Vaughan, Sarah Hallowell
    - ALS to [Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835], n.d.; 1 p.; Vaughan, Samuel, 1762-1827
    - ALS to Vaughan, Sarah Manning, 1795 August 4; 1 p.; Lindsay, George
    - ALS to [Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835], 1795 July 29; 1 p.; Vaughan, Sarah Hallowell
  - Benjamin Franklin on Animal Magnetism, 1785; No. 15
    - AMs, Dr. Franklin's Report on Animal Magnetism, 1785
  - Unitarian church, Walthamstow, England, Minutes of vestry meetings, 1778-1779; No. 16
    - AMs, Unitarian church, Walthamstow, England, Minutes of vestry meetings, 1778-1779; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
- Series V. Bound volumes, B V46p.m; 24 items, 3 linear feet
  Miscellaneous bound manuscript volumes on various topics kept at Hallowell by Benjamin Vaughan and other members of his family. Among the volumes are a catalog of the books left by Samuel Vaughan, 1823; a cash book and account book kept by Petty Vaughan, 1813-1821 and 1816-1817; and an account book of William Oliver Vaughan, 1818.
  Seven of the bound volumes bear a more direct relationship to Benjamin Vaughan: a lecture on moral philosophy delivered by John Aikin (1713-1780) at the Warrington Academy, 1767; two notebooks and a chronology of ancient history, 1773-1775, and two volumes of "abridgments of books examined," including comments on Locke, ca.1760s-1779s. The most significant of these is a moral philosophical treatise, Enquiries Concerning Man, a massive manuscript work apparently written in the third quarter of the 18th century.
  - Vaughan, Benjamin. [Manuscript volumes], 1767-1835, n.d.
    - Vaughan, Samuel. Catalogues of books and maps; 12 7/8 x 8 3/8 in. 176 + 5 unbound p. (46 blank). Contains "Catalogue of the books & maps left by Samuel Vaughan to Samuel Vaughan, Jr. & deposited with Benjn. Vaughan Esq. at Hallowell"; "Catalogue of books sent from Jamaica to Hallowell in 2 shipments between the years 1820-2. The first shipment lodged at Brunswick College & perhaps the 2nd shipment also"; "Catalogue of books left with the minerals at Philadelphia at the Philosl. Hall.", 19 Nov. 1823.; 1
    - Vaughan, Petty. Cash book; 7 3/4 x 6 1/2 in. 253 p. (18 blank). Contains household accounts., April 1813-November 1821.; 2
    - [Account book]; 8 x 6 5/8 in. 265 p. Hallowell, [Me.]., June 1816-Sept. 1817.; 3
    - Vaughan, W[illiam] Oliver. Account book; 7 3/4 x 5 1/2 in. 411 p. (79 blank). Bound throughout with pages from the 1818 Farmer's Almanac. Also includes letters to "Papa" by Benjamin Vaughan, 1818. Oct.-Dec. 1849.; 4
    - Vaughan, W[illiam] M. Cash book; 7 7/8 x 6 5/8 in. 119 p. (25 blank). Contains expenses in Brunswick (Me.), Boston (Mass.), and Calcutta, India., June 1824-August 1835.; 5
    - Vaughan, Benjamin. Lectures in moral philosophy as delivered by the Revd. Mr. Aikin at the Academy of Warrington; 8 1/4 x 6 1/2 in. 164 p. (124 blank). In shorthand., 4 Feb.-18 Mar. 1767.; 6
    - An enquiry concerning man; or the capacities & powers, rights & duties, interests & hopes of mankind delineated: the ways of providence towards them vindicated: and all the laws of nature & nations methodically deduced from incontestable principles; 10 1/2 x 9 1/2 in. 518 p. (34 blank)., 7
    - [Notebook on ancient history of Rome]; 9 5/8 x 7 3/4 in. 271 p., 1773.; 8
    - [Notebook on ancient Greek & Persian history]; 9 5/8 x 7 1/2 in. 257 p. Contains "History of Greece" (p.1-25); "History of the Persians & Grecians" (p. 27-257). "2" written on spine., [1775?]-1776.; 9
    - Chronology [of Lacedaemon, Corinth, Thebes, and Athens]; 9 x 7 1/2 in. 24 p. (20 blank)., 10
    - Abridgements of book examined; 8 1/8 x 6 1/2 in. 181 p. (96 blank). In shorthand. Contains "A short acct. of Locke's answer to Sr. Robert Filmer's Patriarchia"; "Abstract from Locke of government"; "Abridgement of Locke of civil government"; "An abridgement of an essay upon civil government. According to the principles of Fineton. Printed by Randal Minshull 1722. Translated from the French"; "An Abridgement of Harrington's Oceana. Read anno 1769.", 11
    - [Abridgements of books examined; 8 1/4 x 6 5/8 in. 177 p. + 2 unbound (85 blank). In shorthand. Contains "Reflexions upon the insufficiency of language learning"; "Fontenelle's plurality of worlds"; "Cowper's essay at the end of his sitters on taste. R.G.J. Dodsley 1757. 3rd Edit."; "Hume of the different species of philosophy"; "Heberden on poisons"; "Le Clerc's letter on inspiration. London. 1750"; "History of botany from Roger Florce Leyden"; "An essay on the subjects of chemistry and their general division by R. Watson of Cambridge"; "Abbé Winkelman's reflexion on the imitation of the painting of sculpture of the greeks"; "Acct. of a mummy in the cabinets of antiquities at Dresden"; "Knox's history of the campaigns 1757-60 in North America"; "Wharton's history of English poetry.", 12
    - Vaughan, William M. Le[d]ger of Hitchcock's new method of teaching the art of book-keeping; 10 7/8 x 7 7/8. 16 p. printed, 24 p. manuscript., Jan.-Mar. 1822.; 13
    - Vaughan, William M. A new method of teaching the art of book-keeping; 11 x 7 7/8 in. 25 p. printed, 10 p. manuscript., [1822?].; 14
    - [Notes on accounting; 7 7/8 x 6 1/4 in. 180 p. (29 blank). Contains notes on interest & discount, position, exchange, profit & loss, progression, permutation, and vulgar fractions., 15
    - [Shorthand notebook; 7 3/4 x 6 1/2 in. 13 p. (2 blank)., 16
    - [Shorthand notes on many subjects; 8 1/4 x 6 1/2 in. 180 p. (95 blank). Subjects include natural philosophy, relations of identity & diversity, Dioclesian persecutions, church history. Contains longhand notes about beams., 17
    - [Lectures in shorthand; 8 1/8 x 6 1/2 in. 178 p. (76 blank)., 18
    - [Scrapbook of engravings (some containing inspirational verses for children), pencil drawings of animals, people, and houses, and some accounting notes]; 7 7/8 x 5 in. 150 p. Occasional annotations by Mary Vaughan and Anna Caroline Warren Glidden in June & July 1899. Many pages cut out. Mentions Sam Vaughan and Carrie Vaughan in children's drawings. "William Vaugh[a]n alias B. Vaugh[a]n" on endpaper., 1821.; 19
    - [Engravings of country scenes; 8 1/4 x 6 in. 6 leaves. 2 each of 6 engravings (1 of each is colored)., n.d.].; 20
    - [Scrapbook of engravings illustrating biblical events from the Old Testament; 10 1/4 x 6 in. 83 leaves (11 blank). "1" embossed on spine., n.d.].; 21
    - [Scrapbook of engravings illustrating biblical events from the New Testament; 10 1/4 x 6 in. 82 leaves (26 blank). "2" embossed on spine., n.d.].; 22
    - [Sketchbook; 16 3/4 x 12 in. 10 leaves (3 blank). 7 pencil sketches., n.d.].; 23
    - [Music notebook; 6 1/2 x 4 in. 112 p. (56 blank)., n.d.].; 24